Harmanjeet Singh Nagi

https://www.hrmnjt.dev

Email: hrmnjt@hrmn.in Github: hrmnjt Linkedin: hrmnjt

About - Engineering Manager with a knack for building and scaling highly productive teams and systems. I'm passionate about open source, developer experience and systems engineering. Consistently promoted and selected among top 1% performers, resulting in continious leadership development and role expansion.

Experience

Majid Al Futtaim

Dubai, UAE

Engineering Manager (Tribe Lead)

Sep 2021 - Present

- Employ product and data knwoledge to design & implement 2 commercial data-intensive products in business intelligence and ad-marketing space
- Leading a talented team of 24 engineers to self-organize, own and implement an active product roadmap. Ran a Spotify-inspired agile model to arrange team in tribe and squads - 2 squads building a solutions and 3rd squad implementing a commerical bought software
- Become the bridge between BD/Sales and PDT team to translate requirements into solutions; created a culture of writing technical design docs (called ADR) and drive implementation within reasonable milestones
- Balance product delivery with sustaining engineering to ensure code can be maintained over time and iterations. Invested ~30% average bandwidth on reducing technical debt and improving scalability
- Be a proponent of open source solutions and convince team to employ learning and practices on observability, orchestration, documentation and security to promote organization culture. Conducted 20+ architecture review and actively participated in >70 hiring discussions over last year

Lead Data Engineer Jun 2019 - Sep 2021

- Started as an individual contributer to handle central data infrastructure for MAF i.e. integration with 30+ source/sink, data observability and managing databases, data-lake, reporting and event-bus infrastructure
- Scaled a team from 5 to 24 engineers over 2 years to create Data Engineering and Operations team backing up the data operations required for flagship programs run by MAF
- Built an internal product as an extension to bring intelligence to marketing platform. Post 3 month build phase with 9 engineers, it was adopted widely; technically it crunched customer base of 24M of 1000+ attributes each to craft a micro-segmented audience in less than 10s.

Mu Sigma Inc. Bangalore, India May 2015 - Jun 2019

Decision Scientist, Apprentice Leader

- For leading US Airline, optimized recommender system to create a 30% significant lift in yearly revenue. Worked on reverse engineering performance of real-time recommendations (based on Oracle RTD) used for airlines check-in process
- For leading UK retailer, built data and platform infrastucuture for retail pricing and inventory management.
- For MAF, built backend and data pipelines for internal employee application serving 46K employees with 150+
- For MAF, built a configuration based framework for to run data integration and ETL tasks. Enabled 140+ data pipelines from 15 varied data sources to enable BI and analytics use cases

Education

PES Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Engineering - Electrical and Electronics

Bangalore, India Jun 2011 - Jun 2015

Skills

- Domains: Product Engineering, Agile Product Managment, Data Engineering, Machine Learning, Business Intelligence and DevSecOps for Marketing, Digital Advertising, Retail, and Lifestyle business
- Languages: Proficient Shell, Python, SQL; Familiar/Learning Scala, JavaScript, Typescript, Golang
- Data Stack: Postgres, SQLite, Vertica, ElasticSearch, Spark, Delta Lake, Confluent Kafka, Cube.dev, Trino, Airflow, Argo, Superset